GABRIEL SILIPI

Software Developer | Front-end Enginner | React.js | Vue.js 3 Work hours (GTM): 11am – 8pm; or (GTM-3): 8am – 5pm;

Cascavel, PR – Brazil +55 45 99915-8412 gabriel.silipi@gmail.com https://github.com/silipi https://linkedin.com/in/gabriel-silipi

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Enginner - React.js | Node at Dextra - Jul/2021 - present (Campinas, Brazil)

- As a front-end developer at Dextra, I developed a project using Micro-frontends Architecture (3 micro, 1 container, Context/Redux Toolkit and events communication); Along with that, I've used:
- HTML, CSS in JS, JavaScript and React 17+;
- React Hooks, JS ES7+ and Material UI (Design System);
- Unit Testing with Jest, React Testing Library (95%+ coverage) and E2E Testing with Cypress;
- Started following along with back-end developers to take Node.js tasks;

Freelancer Fullstack Software Enginner – Sep/2021 – present

- I'm using my free time to deal with freelance projects;
- Currently, at my tech stack, I'm using Vue 3 + Firebase.js and React.js with Node.js RESTful API;

Front-end Developer - React.js | Angular at Linx - Dec/2020 - Jul/2021 (Cascavel, Brazil)

- I developed the front-end of a product called FarmaCloud using React.js and helped another using Angular; With that, I've used:
- HTML, CSS and JavaScript ES6+;
- React.js & Redux, and Context API; Angular and RxJS;
- Electron.js (PDV), Styled-Components, SASS, Boostrap and MaterialUI;
- Axios, Services (Angular) and Formik; Docker, Git and SEMVER;

QA Automated Enginner | JavaScript at TOTVS CRM – May/2020 – Dec/2020 (Cascavel, Brazil)

- Automated and Manual Testing in a CRM application;
- E2E Testing development with Cypress.io and TestCafé, API with Postman API and JMeter (Load Test);
- Manual, Regression, Usability, Functional and Integration Tests;
- Workspace configuration using Docker and Rancher.dev;

Support Tech Analyst at Linx – Nov/2019 – May/2020 (Cascavel, Brazil)

- As a support, I learned a lot about communication and deal with clients, understanding their pain with the software and coming up with a solution to their problems.
- While I was working there, I develop a simple CRUD app using Delphi and Firebird to help another collegues to store and share useful information about problems that they encounter that can help the entire team;

Computer and IT Teacher at Master Scholl Center – Mar/2019 – Nov/20219 (Cascavel, Brazil)

Preparation and presentation of classes for students of different ages;

- Planning, preparation, writing and correction of tests and assessment activities;

I taught classes with the following subjects:

- HTML, CSS, JS, PHP, MySQL and Access,
- Office package (Word, Excel, Powerpoint...),
- Internet Concepts (HTTP, Protocols, Browsers...),
- and Design with Illustrator, Photoshop and Video with Sony Vegas and Premiere;

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATES

Technician in **Analysis and Systems Development** – **Universitity Unicesumar** 2020 – 2023;

- Software Enginnering, Databases, Development using Java, User Interface, Data Structure I, II...

Degree in Mathematics [unfinished] – University Unioeste 2019 – 2020;

- Differential and Integral Calculus I, II, Analytical and Vector Geometry, Geometric Draw...

CERTIFICATES (ONLINE AND PRESENTIAL COURSES):

- React.js Formation Alura (100 hours)
- AWS Solutions Training for Partners: Foundations Technical
- React.js Front To Back Udemy (14 hours)
- The Modern Javascript Bootcamp Udemy (30 hours)
- Modern JavaScript (from Novice to Ninja) Udemy (19 hours)
- Others, not so relevant, in my LinkedIn profile...

TECHNICAL SKILLS

3+ years: HTML, CSS, JavaScript ES6+ and React.js, Git;

2+ years: Node.js, React.js (Hooks 16.8+), Redux Toolkit, Typescript, Docker;

LANGUAGES

English:	Portuguese:	Spanish:
Advanced	Native	Basic

ABOUT ME

I'm a passionated developer. I started learning about web development ~4 years ago, where I see a lot of opportunity for me to grow professionaly. Beyond the lines of code, I'm a proud father, responsible and I like to spend time learning new things.